







Last Active: 27-Nov-20 Last Modified: 27-Nov-20

Verified : L. Phone Number | Email - id

Jump to Section Work Experience | Education | IT Skills | Projects |

Summary

Administration, Groovy

9 Years+ of proven work experience in Information Technology Industry in managing internal and external clients in Application and product support operations across the globe.

Key Area of Expertise include but not limited to handle large teams by developing excellent relationship among team members, promote the culture of automation to reduce effort hours

Excellent skills in Teamwork, Leadership and Communication, having strong Initiative skills, worked both independently and as part of a team.

Vast experience in Managing 24*7 L1/L2 Operations supporting Clients in all Geographical location including but not limited to Northern/Latin America/Europe/Australia/Asia and Middle East.

Leading the whole shift along with Dev/QA and UMT support personal to

deliver the required services

Mentor/coach other technical support engineers (L1+L2+L3).

Proven record of putting the customer first, going the extra mile, and doing what is right.

Work Experience

Rishabh Software as Senior Manager

Mar 2020 to Till Date

As a Senior Operation Analyst

Troubleshooting of the complex issues and provide a workaround if possible.

Maintain a record of the major activities happened on the multiple instances of application servers.

Handle Major incidents, triage them, help in finding the resolution by providing insight and support from the relevant team.

Conduct root cause analysis and suggest the approach to minimize single point of failure.

Collect operational Stats, find relevant pattern on the resource and operation level by which efficiency can be increased.

Gspann Technologies as Production Support shift lead

Jan 2016 to Feb 2020

Whisk Pvt. Ltd (GSPANN) [Jan-2016 to Feb-2020]

Role : Production Support Shift Lead Duration : Jan 2016 to Feb-20 : Macys, Bloomingdales/STARS Project

Domain: Ecommerce

Technologies : Automation, SSP UI, Programmatic Platform, Exchange, Java, Linux, Oracle

Responsibilities

To ensure prompt addressing of any Client query within defined SLA thresholds.

To ensure team adhere to incident management process, especially all high severity incidents are followed with

Important

· Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld

ucinica galacinics.

To maintain and promote the culture of innovation in team, team has developed many scripts which has made workload reduced by at least 20 %

for team and allowed team to get involved in more L2/L3 activities rather than be involved in repeated monitoring tasks. Leading the bridge for High severity incidents irrespective of day/time, working as a third escalation path after Lead, helping team in finding root cause of issues wherever needed by looking at Java Exceptions/logs/Unix Scripts

Reviewing confluence at regular intervals - This includes SOP, Support Plan, and Incident Management doc for High

Severity issues, Operation Manual and knowledge confluence.

Accountable for managing the allocated process in relation to the Trust's defined ITIL framework.

Overall responsible for managing the processes and reporting on performance against targets.

Ensure that detailed documentation is produced and maintained for all systems and interfaces.

Adhere to release plan for various interface level changes Weekly/Monthly, IR (Internal Release) & ER (Enhancement

Managing new implementations, integrations, upgrades and additional features, including supervision of projects being delivered by members of the Application Support team.

Managing the team roster. Responsibility includes managing shift/leave plan to ensure no gaps in support.

Hewlett Packard as System Admin

May 2013 to Dec 2015

Role System Admin. : May 2013 to Dec 2015 Duration

: Mobily (Saudi Arabia), Telstra (Australia), T-Mobile (U.S.A) Project

Domain: Telecom

: OS: SuSE-release-Linux, Database: Oracle, Application: Java based Technologies

Responsibilities

Managing shift/leave plan to ensure no gaps in support.

Manage UAT and production Implementation.

Plaanning KT sessiong accross diffferents teams.

Interact with infrastructure, release management, change management, QA, DBA and application teams.

Prioritize issues raised and resolve it accordingly

Report promptly to management and business partners regarding critical outages until resolution Reviewing documents for any new change - Implementation Plans, Run Books, DRR (Deployment Readiness Review),

ORC/ORT (Operational Readiness Checklist/Testing Review) and Issue book.

Managing new implementations, integrations, upgrades and additional features, including supervision of projects

being delivered by members of the Application Support team.

Working proactively with the team to reduce LOE of repetitive task.

Delivering the work as per benchmark with quality standards and consistently exceeding client expectations.

Ensuring timely deliverable before deadline.

Release Management and Performance Improvement Audits.

Incident Management and ad-hoc requirements from users.

Deriving Support related call/meetings.

Suntech Web services Pvt. Ltd as Support Tech Lead

Jul 2011 to Apr 2013

Suntech Webservices Pvt Ltd. [July 2011 to April 2013]

: Level-I Production Support Engineer Role

: July 2011 to Apr 2013 Duration

: Neustar (Comcast + TWC + Charter) - U.S.A Proiect

Domain: Telecom

: OS: Linux, Database: Oracle, Application: VB.net/Java **Technologies**

Responsibilities

Performed UAT and production Implementation.

Involement in issue debuggin and fixinng.

Participation in bug review meetinng with project manager/QE an Dev team.

Attend ticket/issue disucustion with customer.

Lead UAT and production Implementation.

Plaanning KT sessiong accross diffferent-2 teams.
Designing system health report and get these implemnted on production.

Lead team to automate Syste and application health report.

Working proactively with the team to reduce LOE of repetitive task.

Audit of bugs/issues via ticking system, investigate further if required until closure. Manage shift in absent of Shift manager.

Doing L2 level investigation on issue reported by Level1 team or Client.

Publish Incident update/ICA/RCA

Involved in UAT testing at various stages.

Working proactively with the team to reduce LOE of repetitive task.

Ensure issue investigated or escalated to next leave within defined SLA

Preparing Syteam and Aplication Helath check report.

Doing L1 level analysis on issue reported.

Involved in logging the Defects, Defect Reporting and Tracking.

Preparing the Daily status Reports & Weekly Status Reports etc.

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from Pune University in 2011

PG: in 0

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

ITIL Certified

^ Back to Top

II ONIIIS

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
ORACLE, MYSQL			
SQL/PLSQL, Shell Scripting, JAVA, HTML,			
JavaScript			
JIRA, Tick-Track, BMC Remedy			
GIT		0	0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
WEB SERVICES		2020	0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Proficient	✓	✓	✓
Hindi	Proficient	✓	✓	✓
Punjabi	Proficient			

^ Back to Top

Projects

Project Title: Programmatic Exchange (Trading) Client: JCDecaux Advertising (MOOH - U.K)

Nature of Employment: Full Time
Project Location: Pune
Role: Other
Duration: Mar 2020 - Till Date
Onsite / Offsite: Offsite
Role: Other
Team Size: 26

Project Details: SSP UI, Automation, Exchange Trading with DSP through RTB with different Media Owners and DSPs.

Project Title: STARS

Client: Macys

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Jan 2016 - Feb 2020
Project Location: Gurgaon Onsite / Offsite: Offsite
Team Size: 22

Project Details: Production Support Shift Lead, Team Lead/Tech Lead, System Administration, Incident Management, Technical Support, Change Management, Application Management, UMT Support, SLAManagement, Project Management, Problem Management, Product Support, MYSQL, HTML, Java

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: General Job Type: Permanent
Physically Challenged: No Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQs - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.